Catalina Romila

E-mail: catalina.romila@hotmail.co.uk

Profile

Self-driven individual, desire for learning new skills and who enjoys challenges. Resilience and resourcefulness are personal qualities, along with great enthusiasm and enormous potential. I have a proven track record of great ability to work as part of a team as well as individually. I have start-up, entrepreneurship, business innovation, as well as programming and front-end developer experience.

Education

University – University College London (2015-2019)

PhD - 'High-Throughput Chronological Lifespan Screening of the Fission Yeast Deletion Library Using Barcode Sequencing'

University – Queen Mary, University of London (2012-2015)

BSc in Biochemistry – 1st class with Honours.

Laboratory Techniques

Handling of fission yeast and fruit fly as model organisms; lifespan experiments; microscopy; molecular techniques such as DNA and RNA extraction; PCRs; qPCR; FACs; DNA & RNA library preparation and sequencing; DNA-seq & RNA-seq data analysis.

Computational Skills

- Extensive experience in R, bash, HTML & CSS.
- Limited training in Python, SQL & Git.
- Proficient in Microsoft Office.

Relevant Experience

Teaching assistant (October 2015 – February 2019): UCL, Gower Street, London, WC1E 6BT. In this role I was a demonstrator helping lecturers deliver their practicals to undergraduate students. Key Responsibilities:

- Prepare teaching material;
- Room and/or equipment booking;
- Deliver the practical session/seminar while being inclusive and as interactive as possible;
- Mark student's essays and provide constructive feedback;

IMAGINE!IF Accelerator Programme Global Administrator (2018): UCL, Gower Street, London, WC1E 6BT.

In this role I collaborated and work together with branch representatives all over the world to help organise the Global IMAGINE!IF Accelerator Programme competition for star-ups within the biotech/cleantech/healthcare system.

Key Responsibilities:

- Lease with potential partners, mentors and judges;
- Content creator to increase social media presence;
- Receiving, initial screening and distribution of accelerator applications;
- Regular call meetings to update on progress and strategies our next steps;

Associate Management at Innovation Forum (2017- 2018): UCL, Gower Street, London, WC1E 6BT.

This is a student lead UCL branch organisation representing the global Innovation Forum, a non-for-profit organisation that works to synergise relationships between academia and industry.

Key Responsibilities:

- Organising events and start-up related workshops;
- Aiding with sponsorship requirement;
- Day to day management included, attending meetings, venue bookings, marketing and advertising.

Three-month Intern at Allen & Overy (2018): One Bishops Square, London E1 6AD.

This was a fantastic opportunity to learn about intellectual property (IP) within a business setting in more depth. Areas introduced and trained included:

- Registered rights e.g. patenting
- Unregistered rights e.g. copyrights
- IP strategy, marking and advantages
- IP exploitation, policy and enforcement.

Key Responsibilities:

- Content creation as supporting documents for various clients;
- Presenting, analysing and disseminating scientific data;
- Aiding with court hearing preparations, attending the hearing and reporting outcome to the team;
- Regular meetings and client calls attendance.

Enterprise Bootcamp & Start-up (5 & 3 days, respectively, 2016): UCL, Gower Street, London, WC1E 6BT.

These were 'learning-through-doing' experiences. In both instances, I worked as a group of 7 and started from an idea all the way through to the pitching of the newly developed product.

The topics exploited included:

- **Innovation and market research:** accounting for existing products, competitors and niche markets.
- **Business models:** exploiting different business models such as the 'lock in' and 'freemium' strategies.
- Value proposition design and testing: focusing on customer needs and existing 'pain relivers'.
- **Finance and financial planning:** considering manufacturing prices, forecasting sales and cashflows.
- **Pitch:** delivery of the newly developed product to an angels' panel.

Hobbies & Achievements

Current hobbies include but not limited to gym, cycling, cooking and reading.

A list of most up to date achievements is provided below:

- Front-end developer certificate (2019);
- Higher Education Associate Fellowship (2018);
- Prize for best social enterprise project idea (2018);
- Recipient of two prestigious UCL bursaries (2018);
- Summer internship funded by the RSC (2015);

- Whittingham prize for outstanding academic achievement (2015).